Finding Aid for Department of Nuclear Engineering and Radiological Sciences (University of Michigan) publications, 1954-ongoing
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Department of Nuclear Engineering and Radiological Sciences (University of Michigan) publications 1954-ongoing
University of Michigan. Department of Nuclear Engineering and Radiological Sciences.
2 linear feet
971; Bimu; C146; 2
Department of the University of Michigan College of Engineering. Includes annual reports, bibliographies, miscellaneous brochures and bulletins from the Dept. of Nuclear Engineering. Also includes an alumni directory published for the twenty-fifth anniversary of the department. Contains three newsletters entitled Engineering Alumni Newsletter, Nuclear Engineering and Radiological Sciences Alumni, and NERS Notes: Alumni Newsletter in addition to annual reports and brochures from the Michigan Ion Beam Laboratory.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The publications are received periodically from the unit (Donor No. 8371 )
The publications are open without restriction.
The University of Michigan Department of Nuclear Engineering and Radiological Sciences (NERS) research cuts across boundaries of disciplines to find solutions to real-world problems in four major areas: sustainable energy; nuclear security and defense; environment and health; enabling scientific discovery.
The University of Michigan Department of Nuclear Engineering and Radiological Sciences Publications are divided into four series: Unit Publications, Sub-Unit Publications, Topical Publications and Student Publications. The bulk of the publications document the Department of Nuclear Engineering and Radiological Sciences and the research of its faculty and students.
Subjects:
University of Michigan. Department of Nuclear Engineering.; University of Michigan. Michigan Ion Beam Laboratory.; Annual reports.; Newsletters.; Pamphlets.; University of Michigan. Department of Nuclear Engineering and Radiological Sciences.
Contributors:
University of Michigan. Michigan Ion Beam Laboratory.; University of Michigan. Department of Nuclear Engineering.
Genre Terms:
Bibliographies.; Directories.
- Unit Publications
  The Unit Publications series contains printed material published specifically by the Department of Nuclear Engineering and Radiological Sciences. These publications are defined as being widely distributed and may be published at regular intervals. They are arranged by genre of the publication.
  The Unit Publications series includes annual reports, bibliographies, brochures, bulletins, directories, newsletters, posters, programs, and reports. The annual reports run from 1995 to 2007. There is also an annual report documenting the 1975/1976 academic year. Bibliographies include the Doctoral Theses in Nuclear Engineering documenting the period from 1992 to 1994. The Faculty and Student Publications bibliography covers the same period. The bulletins describe the graduate program in Nuclear Engineering at the University of Michigan from 1967 to 1977 and 1990 to 1999. The twenty-fifth anniversary of the department was celebrated in June 1983. At that time the department published a 25th Anniversary Program and Alumni Roster. This directory includes both a short history of the department and a list of alumni, degrees, years of graduation, current positions, employers, and a brief description of their work. The internal newsletter Nuclear Engineering Newsletter was published from 1990 to 1994 and documents the activities of the department, faculty, staff, and students. The department also published newsletters for its alumni. The Bentley Historical Library holds these titles: the Nuclear Engineering Alumni Newsletter issued in 1994, the Nuclear Engineering and Radiological Sciences Alumni Newsletter released from 1996 to 1997, and NERS Notes: Alumni Newsletter printed from 1997 to 2007. Starting in the academic year 2002/2003, a CD-ROM was created for recruiting information. Recruitment CD-ROM's include admissions information and applications, graduate brochure, facilities description, faculty/staff profiles, list of courses and description of research areas.
  - Annual Reports
    - Annual Report (Box 1)
      - 1975-1976 (Box 1)
      - 1995-1998, 3 folders (Box 1)
      - 1999-2007, 8 folders (Box 1)
  - Bibliographies
    - Doctoral Theses in Nuclear Engineering, 1994 (Box 1)
    - Faculty and Student Publications..., 1994 (Box 1)
  - Brochures
    - General 1973-1994, undated (Box 1)
    - Awards and Distinctions, 1994 (Box 1)
    - Graduate Programs, 1994, undated (Box 1)
    - Nuclear Engineering, 1967-1995, undated (Box 1)
  - Bulletins
    - Information on Graduate Programs, 1967-1977 (Box 1)
    - Graduate Study in Nuclear Engineering..., 1990-1994, 1999, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Directories
    - Twenty-fifth Anniversary Program and Alumni Roster, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Newsletters
    - E-Mail Newsletter, 1995 (Box 1)
    - NERS Notes: Alumni Newsletter, 1997-2007, 3 folders (Box 1)
    - Nuclear Engineering, 1967 (Box 1)
    - Nuclear Engineering Alumni Newsletter, 1994 (Box 1)
    - Nuclear Engineering and Radiological Sciences Alumni Newsletter, 1996-1997 (Box 1)
    - Nuclear Engineering Newsletter, 1990-1994, 4 folders (Box 1)
  - Posters
    - 1991-2006 (Box 1)
    - Proceedings, Symposium on Energy and the Environment 2002 (Box 1)
    - Recruitment CD-ROMs 2002-2009 (Box 1)
  - Programs
    - 1954-1992 (Box 1)
  - Reports
    - Anomalous Transmission of Intense CO2 Laser Radiation Through an Overdense Plasma, 1977 (Box 1)
    - Fresnel Diffraction From a Circular Aperture Produced by a CO2 Laser in Dense Helium Z-Pinch by Duncan G. Steel and David R. Bach, 1976 (Box 1)
    - Rayleigh Scattering of Ruby Laser Light in Neutral Gases by Ralph R. Rudder and David R. Bach, 1967 (Box 1)
    - Scattering of Light from Atoms, Molecules and Free Electrons in Gases and Plasmas by Carl M. Penney, 1965 (Box 1)
    - Solitary Alfven Wave-Guide Structures in a Magnetized Plasma, by J.P. Sheerin and R.S.B. Ong, 1979 (Box 1)
    - Te125 Mossbauer Effect Study of Radiation Effects and Magnetic Hyperfine Structure in Tellurium Compounds by John F. Ullrich and Dietrich H. Vincent, 1967 (Box 2)
    - Thermal Self-Focusing of a Laser Beam in a Dense, Low Temperature Plasma by R.S.B. Ong and Andrew Schmitt, 1979 (Box 2)
- Sub-Unit Publications
  The Sub-Unit Publications series contains publications from subordinate offices, departments, programs and organizations within the Department of Nuclear Engineering and Radiological Sciences. These publications are arranged alphabetically by the creating sub-unit include publications from the Electric Power Research Institute, the Michigan Ion Beam Laboratory, Radiological Health Engineering, and Robotics for Advanced Reactors.
  - Electric Power Research Institute
    - Reports
      - Simplified Models for Transient Analysis of Nuclear Steam Generators, 1981 (Box 2)
      - Transient Modeling of Steam Generator Units in Nuclear Power Plants: Computer Code, TRANSG-01, 1980 (Box 2)
  - Michigan Ion Beam Laboratory
    - Annual Reports
      - Annual Research Reports, 1987-1989 (Box 2)
    - Brochures
      - undated (Box 2)
      - Michigan Ion Beam Laboratory For Surface Modification and Analysis, undated (Box 2)
  - Radiological Health Engineering
    - Brochures 1994, undated (Box 2)
  - Robotics for Advanced Reactors
    - Brochures undated (Box 2)
- Topical Publications
  The Topical Publications series includes printed materials published to document specific events or activities such as fund-raising or one-time conferences hosted by the Department of Nuclear Engineering and Radiological Sciences. The series also contains directories from the American Nuclear Society, published from 1990 to 1993, which include biographical information on various faculty members of the department.
  - American Nuclear Society
    The Student Publications series contains publications published by student groups within the Department of Nuclear Engineering and Radiological Sciences. The series contains a flyer documenting a fund-raiser by the University of Michigan Nuclear Society.
    - Directories
      - Education Sourcebook, 1990-1993, 4 folders (Box 2)
- Student Publications
  The series contains publications published by student groups withing the Department of Nuclear Engineering and Radiological Sciences.
  - U of M Nuclear Society
    - Flyers 1995 (Box 2)